<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mardan</title>
    <description>Mardan&#39;s site for reviews, blogs, and other random stuff.
</description>
    <link>http://rittbys.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rittbys.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:28:51 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:28:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Borderlands 2: Tiny Tina&#39;s Assault on Dragon Keep Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Borderlands 2: Tiny Tina’s Assault on Dragon Keep is one of the four campaign DLCs made for Borderlands 2. It was developed by Gearbox Software, the developers of the base game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It follows a DnD-esque board game being played by Lilith, Brick, Mordecai, and Tina as the Dungeon Master. You play one of the pieces on the table, battling dragons and other fantastical creatures as the world changes around you at the whim of Tina and the others. The world is really thematic while maintaining the same Borderlands feel of the base game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is a very cliche DnD game story, rescue a princess from the evil wizard who’s corrupting the land. At the same time, though, you can still hear the characters talking as they play the board game, and you can hear the real plot of &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;Tina’s denial of Roland’s death, and the other characters’ attempts to get her to cope with it.&lt;/span&gt; Characters from the base game make an appearance, some in their normal forms and others as part of the game world. All the vending machines have been spruced up with stained glass renditions of their Pandoran counterparts. One tiny anomaly that I noticed is that the reflections in the water of Flamerock Refuge are reflections of Sanctuary’s buildings. Whether or not this is intentional is up to speculation. I love how it’s constantly making references to other fantasy games or other media, and there’s even one quest where you have to troll some other ‘players’ who are waiting for a mob to respawn into leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DLC weapons are also very good, and there’s actually a whole new rarity, Gemstone, that takes its place as just a bit better than purple-rarity. The Magic Missile grenade mods, namely, are some of the best in the game as they allow you to regenerate grenade ammo while they’re equipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-verdict-910---amazing&quot;&gt;Final Verdict: 9/10 - Amazing&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/dlc/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2-tiny-tina.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/dlc/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2-tiny-tina.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
        <category>dlc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Borderlands 2: Sir Hammerlock&#39;s Big Game Hunt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Borderlands 2: Sir Hammerlock’s Big Game Hunt is a piece of DLC for Borderlands 2 that was outsourced by 2K. It follows the adventures of the refined Sir Hammerlock’s adventure through a hunting retreat with your player character. This is one of the four Campaign DLCs for Borderlands 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This DLC takes place in an insect and primitive tribe filled swamp, and they’ve chosen to accentuate this by placing a horrible green filter over everything. All the sub areas in this DLC look almost exactly the same, all with the ugly green filter. There’s very little of the hallmark secret areas or easter eggs to be found in this DLC, making the levels uninteresting and bland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story basically centers around Professor Nakayama, who hijacks your hunting to tell you &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt; that he’s created a clone of Handsome Jack, and tries to entice you to seek him out. &lt;/span&gt; The story is overall very mundane and not well written at all, though I did enjoy &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt; Claptrap being revered as a god a-la-C-3P0 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My major complaint with this DLC is actually the balancing and pacing of enemies. All the enemies are complete bullet sponges, and the witch doctors are downright unfair even in Normal Vault Hunter Mode. The giant floating spores are the most annoying enemies to deal with in the entire game, as they too are bullet sponges. Badass Savages can even be evolved by the Witch Doctors, finally resulting in a form that can only be taken down by fifteen successive point blank Norfleet shots. You’ll even struggle and probably die several times to the first group of enemies in the DLC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This DLC does, however, include Voracidous the Invincible, a raid boss and actually a pretty fun and challenging one. All of the DLC weapons, however, are anything but useful and inventive. Mainly, they’re just slower and lower damage versions of base game weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-verdict-310---terrible-but-with-one-or-two-redeeming-qualities&quot;&gt;Final Verdict: 3/10 - Terrible, but with one or two redeeming qualities&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:33:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/dlc/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2-sir-hammerlock.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/dlc/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2-sir-hammerlock.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
        <category>dlc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Borderlands 2 Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;review-content-header&quot; src=&quot;/images/boxart/borderlands-2/cover1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borderlands 2 is a first person looter shooter developed by Gearbox Software and published by 2K Games. It was ported to Mac &amp;amp; Linux by Aspyr. This is by far my favorite game ever; I love it wholeheartedly. It’s crazy, but a perfect level to where it’s not boring; it’s comedic, but still manages to deliver a moving story. I definitely think that, if you haven’t played this game, you should play it now and grab the DLC while you’re at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;combat--weapons--&quot;&gt;- Combat &amp;amp; Weapons -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combat in Borderlands 2 is incredibly simple at first. Shoot everything without a green health bar. Or sometimes those too. It develops complexity, however, when you gain access to elemental weaponry; these come in the form of fire, shock, corrosive, and slag. The first three deal enhanced damage to a specific type of health (fire to flesh, shock to shields, and corrosive to armor), and slag causes enemies to take more damage from other elemental types. This system works because you can easily opt to use regular ballistic weaponry and not have to worry about it, or use elemental weaponry and deal vastly enhanced damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each weapon has specific characteristics that make it unique. Rarity, level, parts, type, and manufacturer all play their part in making each weapon different. The Rarity influences the skin it will use, as well as enhancing all stats; the level will multiply all stats to make it applicable at high level; the parts will provide stat enhancements to specific stats, as well as visibly changing the weapon’s model; the weapon type (assault rifle, SMG, sniper, pistol, shotgun, etc.); the manufacturer will add a special trait to the weapon (ex. Dahl weapons burst fire when zoomed). There’s a whole lot of depth to be found here, but it’s still very approachable if you don’t want to mess with this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of variety found in weapons greatly adds to the replayability of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-story--&quot;&gt;- The Story -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of Borderlands 2 is actually one of the high points of this game, something you wouldn’t expect from one of these ultra-violent looter shooter games. It focuses on a Vault Hunter, your character, striving to find an ancient alien vault filled with loot hidden away on Pandora, a savage planet filled with vile creatures and vicious raiders. The Hyperion Corporation, led by maniacal antagonist Handsome Jack, is also searching for the vault, and seeks to harness its power to restore Pandora by killing everyone on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borderlands 2 manages that perfect mix of comedy and seriousness that makes the story that much more immersive and believable. The characters, both returning from the first game and new to this one, are unforgettable, as is most of the rest of the game. There’s fantastic writing paired with character depth and fantastic voice acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characters--customization--&quot;&gt;- Characters &amp;amp; Customization -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another strong point of Borderlands 2 is how great the character customization is. You can pick between more heads and body colorings than you can count, and you have four weapon slots in which to equip guns simultaneously. Each class has their own head customizations, skill trees, and action skills. Each class has 3 skill trees (you aren’t limited to one at a time) that each have their own focus. When playing in co-op, the classes work together really well, proving how much time and thought went into tailoring these skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-world--&quot;&gt;- The World -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the levels look completely different from each other, and I could probably tell you which level you were showing me from a small screenshot of it. Almost every level has an easter egg of some sort, ranging from the whole Minecraft area filled with blocks and Creepers found in the Caustic Caverns to the “Rakkman Forever” or “R.O.U.S.” enemies found in The Fridge. They aren’t just “haha memes” easter eggs, they’re incorporated into the world and used at just the right frequency to make them enjoyable instead of annoying. There’ll always be one small detail that I notice every time I come back to a level. Some kind of secret treasure room or hidden vault symbol will always be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each enemy faction feels unique, and you have to fight each one differently. For instance, Loaders will largely just charge you, but Rats and some Hyperion soldiers will try to use cover and distance wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;graphics--performance--&quot;&gt;- Graphics &amp;amp; Performance -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Borderlands series has a unique visual style found in both lighting and textures. It’s not the best lighting or the highest resolution textures to be found out there, but it’s still visually pleasing because of its consistent art style. However, the PC version has a great options menu along with fantastic performance. One gripe is that PhysX seems to be a lot less optimized than the implementation found in The Pre-Sequel!. Another is that the game only features SSAO and FXAA, but you can inject SMAA using ReShade or force MSAA from your graphics control panel. You can also implement HBAO+ as shown in a guide I’ve written for the game on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;something that is not usually possible. Part of the visual style, I think, is the lack of material shaders, making everything look like it was drawn on a piece of paper and then glued to the model. The comical cel shading effect makes this visual style work, where normally it would be atrocious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion--&quot;&gt;- Conclusion -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please buy this game. It’s an amazing looting experience backed up by a fantastic story and great character customization, making it enjoyable even by your fifth playthrough. Even the DLC is good! It’s well optimized, it’s not the most graphically advanced game but it still looks great, and the menus are well designed. Even if you don’t play the co-op game in co-op mode, it’s still very enjoyable and well-balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-verdict-9510---utterly-amazing&quot;&gt;Final Verdict: 9.5/10 - Utterly Amazing&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 09:39:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rittbys.github.io/reviews/2016/02/05/review-borderlands-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Batman: Arkham Knight Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;review-content-header&quot; src=&quot;/images/boxart/batman-arkham-knight/cover1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Batman: Arkham Knight is an open-world action game developed by Rocksteady, published by Warner Brothers, and ported to PC by Iron Galaxy. This game is infamous for its atrocious launch, when it was riddled so much with bugs, frame rate locks, missing features, and general horrible performance that WB felt the need to pull it from shelves and encourage people to get refunds. Now, however, most of the bugs and issues have been ironed out, and it is definitely a fantastic game and an acceptable PC port. Please note that in this review I will be trying not to compare it to previous Arkham games, but I will be using Origins if I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;combat--&quot;&gt;- Combat -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game uses the FreeFlow combat system, as in the previous Arkham games, but this time with new Environmental Takedowns, enemy types, and general combat improvements over previous Arkham games. My main issue with the stealth system in previous games is that it is incredibly difficult, if not near-impossible, to effectively deal with a room full of armed enemies. In Arkham Knight, this issue is addressed by adding a multi-enemy takedown that is earned by pulling off Silent takedowns. The areas have more vertical depth, and you can enter grates from the vantage points. A new gadget, the Voice Synthesizer, allows you to actually order enemies around once you obtain it. The Disruptor has received a major buff as well, now having 4 shots total (after one upgrade), and it can disable even more weapons and environmental objects. The addition of automated turrets adds another layer of challenge in that you have to disable their sensors using the Remote Hacking Device and knock out all the enemies in 60 seconds before it comes back online and guns you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-open-world--&quot;&gt;- The Open World -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the strong points of this game is how good it feels to just move around the open world, be it in the Batmobile crushing through buildings and crowds of rioters as you zoom along the streets of Gotham, or flying amongst the tallest buildings and grappling you way to your goal, it just feels good. The Grapnel Accelerator has also received a buff, allowing you to boost yourself 5 times (after 3 upgrades), becoming insanely fast. It can be infuriating, however, to mash your space bar so much every time you grapple to a new location. The mandatory “Open-World-game-collectible-items” are here again in the form of, again, Riddler Trophies. Riddler Trophies will either take the form of items that you merely have to go to the right location to pick up, or rewards for completing puzzles. You can find the location of Riddler Trophies by interrogating Riddler Informants that will randomly spawn throughout Gotham. In previous Arkham games, you could actually take down the Riddler Informant and still interrogate him afterwards, but in Arkham Knight you must keep them alive, which can get infuriating pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotham is divided into three islands, Founders Island (The hardest), Miagani Island, and Bleake Island (The easiest). You start out on Bleake Island, but can fly to the other islands any time you wish. You cannot, however, drive the Batmobile to the other islands until you lower the bridges at some point in the main story quest. Each island has a “threat level”, which denotes how many drone tanks/checkpoints/watchtowers/quadcopters the main enemy has remaining on each island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-batmobile--&quot;&gt;- The Batmobile -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Batmobile is Batman’s personal car that you can drive around almost at your leisure. At almost any point in the game, you can press a button when looking at a street and the Batmobile will be summoned to your location. The Batmobile can also turn into a maneuverable tank by holding RMB, in which mode you are armed with Riot Suppressors (nonlethal rounds), two Vulkan guns, and a 60mm cannon. As the story progresses, you are given more secondary weapons, which you can use after charge is build up by blowing up more tanks in the Batmobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the Batmobile, I really do. However, the game forces you to use it waaaay too much for my taste, and it starts to feel a bit weird the more you use it. First off, let’s just point out that Gotham’s streets are full of objects. Boxes, walls, pillars, even those portable toilet things are lining the streets in Arkham Knight. Instead of having these objects as permanent obstructions to the Batmobile, Rocksteady opted to make almost all of these objects destructible with either your twin machine guns, 60mm cannon, or just by rolling over them. This kind of goes against Batman’s motto somewhat, as he’s incurring enough property damage to probably collapse a building on some poor crowd who went to the “Prometheus Academy of Running Away from Things.” On top of that, it just feels like…everything is made of weak foam. There’s very little resistance on anything, even solid concrete pillars supporting buildings. It creates this weird feeling of non-substance on the car, something that you never want when designing a driving mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;graphics--performance--&quot;&gt;- Graphics &amp;amp; Performance -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it, it’s not a perfect PC port by any means. It will drop to 45 frames per second in some areas. The GameWorks smoke WILL destroy your framerate whenever you rev up the Batmobile. However, I ran with these settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;review-content-image&quot; src=&quot;/images/boxart/batman-arkham-knight/options.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and had an overall amazing graphical experience that is well suited to a modern AAA title. The GameWorks Smoke &amp;amp; Fog effect is an absolute waste, So I turned it off immediately, but the other effects actually look quite good and don’t have much of a performance hit as far as I could tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game just looks…amazing. By far one of the best looking games ever released, it boasts excellent lighting, wetness effects, reflections, the best rain I’ve ever seen, particle effects, and cloth on Batman’s cape. I have to criticize their off-looking skin effects, however. It’s almost as if it’s trying to be SubSurface Scattering, but isn’t quite there. Nevertheless, it looks great and it runs fairly well on my system (i7 4790k/GTX 970).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch, there was a controversy over the PC version missing wetness textures, but I can assure you that they’re present now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;review-content-image&quot; src=&quot;/images/boxart/batman-arkham-knight/rain-textures.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-story--&quot;&gt;- The Story -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story revolves around the Arkham Knight, a mysterious masked villain who’s out for revenge on Batman, and Scarecrow. The Knight is actually a new character created exclusively for this game, which is failrly uncommon to see in a DC game. I won’t spoil the specifics of the plot twist here, but &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;Batman’s slow decent into insanity is very very well done, more than most. The game really overuses the “you turn around and turn back and there’s something different there now” though.&lt;/span&gt; Scarecrow has threatened Gotham with his new batch of fear toxin, and Gotham is evacuated, leaving the Arkham Knight’s militia to take control of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really felt intimidated by Scarecrow as a main villain up until now, he’s always been just that guy who wears a bag on his head. In Arkham Knight, however, a combination of his redesign and his fantastic voice acting by John Noble (I just have to mention it) creates a genuinely fear-inducing antagonist. In fact, all the characters are very well voice acted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the story is very well written and touches on the different characters for just the right amount of time before moving on. Almost every mission feels unique, and they all tie together very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion--&quot;&gt;- Conclusion -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would talk more about this game, but the character limit is cutting me a bit short here. Overall, Arkham Knight has fantastic combat, graphics, and story, and overall great side activities and open world. I’ve explored every inch of this Gotham, and I encourage you to do so as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-verdict-8510---fantastic-but-with-a-few-flaws&quot;&gt;Final Verdict: 8.5/10 - Fantastic but with a few flaws&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:40:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rittbys.github.io/post/2016/01/28/review-batman-arkham-knight.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rittbys.github.io/post/2016/01/28/review-batman-arkham-knight.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
